thehighline.org 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy | The High Line

### Privacy Policy

_Last Updated on August 30, 2018_

Welcome to thehighline.org (the “website”), which is owned and operated by the Friends of the High Line (“FHL,” “we,” “us,” or “our”). FHL has adopted this Privacy Policy to inform you of its policies with respect to information collected from both online and offline users. Your use of this website, communications, and involvement in our programs and events, constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, and your consent to the practices they describe.

_See our Donor Privacy Policy_

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT  
**  
In general, we collect Personal Information when you communicate with us and when you use the website. When FHL uses the term “Personal Information,” we mean information that we directly associate with a specific person, or that can reasonably be used to identify a specific person such as a name, address, telephone number, email address, or Internet Protocol (IP) address. The website collects some information from you that is voluntarily provided by you, and other information that is collected by the website automatically. Additionally, we may collect Personal Information about you from other third-parties and combine it with our records, for example, to update your contact information.

**Personal Information You Provide to Us  
**  
Through your use of the website and interactions with FHL you may provide FHL with the following Personal Information:  
• name  
• status (such as whether you are a patron or a donor)  
• contact Information (for example an e-mail address, mailing address, or phone number)  
• username and password  
• transaction and payment Information (such as billing address and donation frequency and preferences)  
• event registration information (including both you and your guests’ Personal Information)  
• job application information (including demographic information, education, work history, and any other relevant information you share with us through your application)  
• information collected through our use of cookies

FHL may also collect Personal Information about you from third-parties, and may combine it with other Personal Information. For example, we may ask a third-party to help us update your contact information in our records.

**Personal Information Automatically Collected Through Your Use of the Website  
**  
When you visit the FHL website, certain information about your visit is automatically logged, which may include information about the type of browser you use, the server name and IP address through which you access the Internet, the date and time you access the site, the pages you access while at the FHL website, Internet service provider information, device type, and the Internet address of the website, if any, from which you linked directly to, or depart from, the website.

We may collect information about your location when you access or use the website. We may also collect information regarding your general location using your IP address. If you access or use the website from a mobile device, we may collect more precise geolocation information from your mobile device. You can disable geolocation services in the settings on your mobile device.

**HOW WE USE AND SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION  
**  
**Use of Personal Information**  
  
In general, we use information collected about you to: (i) enable you to log into and use the website; (ii) communicate with you; (iii) enable you to register for events; (iv) collect and process donations; (v) administer assistance to you when requested; and (vi) as otherwise permitted or required by applicable laws, rules, or regulations or the Terms of Use applicable to this website.

FHL may use the Personal Information to:  
• help establish and verify the identity of users  
• open, maintain, administer, and service users’ accounts or memberships  
• process or service transactions and donations, and send related communications  
• provide services and support to users  
• provide users with updates, notices, invitations, and other information about FHL  
• request monetary contributions  
• respond to job applications and related inquiries  
• respond to your questions, inquiries, and comments  
• improve the website, including tailoring it to the users’ preferences  
• maintain the security and integrity of our systems  
• or as otherwise permitted or required under applicable law

**Disclosure of Personal Information**  
  
FHL may share your information with our partner, the New York City Department of Parks & Recreation. FHL may also use third-party vendors to help us maintain and operate our website and to operate our business, and those vendors may receive your Personal Information for those limited purposes. FHL may also disclose Personal Information about you in connection with legal requirements, such as in response to a subpoena, governmental request, or investigation, or as otherwise required by law. In certain instances, we may agree to allow a vendor to use aggregated data about activity for general improvement or benchmarking purposes, generally in an anonymized or aggregate form.

We also may share your Personal Information with third-parties for any legitimate business purpose, or if we believe that the law requires us to do so, or to protect our property or the property of our partner and/or affiliates. Additionally, in the event of a corporate restructuring (such as a sale, merger, or other transfer of some or all of our asset), we may share your Personal Information with a third party. We reserve the right to use or disclose any information in aggregate form, for any purpose, in our sole judgment.

**Use and Disclosure of Information for Mailing Lists  
**  
We may occasionally share users’ names and postal addresses with carefully selected nonprofit organizations. While we do not currently share email addresses or phone numbers with any unaffiliated third-parties, we may decide to do so in the future. If you do not want your information exchanged in this way, please contact our Membership Department to ask that your name and address be removed from any shared mailing lists at [members@thehighline.org](mailto:members@thehighline.org), or by calling 212-206-9922.

**CHILDREN’S PRIVACY ON OUR WEBSITE  
**  
This website is not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly attempt to solicit or receive Personal Information from children under 13. If FHL discovers that it has received Personal Information from an individual reasonably believed to under the age of 13, FHL will delete such information from its systems. If you are the parent or legal guardian and you believe we may have inadvertently collected Personal Information from a child under 13, please contact us to request the child’s information be deleted by contacting us at [privacy@thehighline.org](mailto:privacy@thehighline.org).

**“COOKIES” AND ADVERTISERS  
**  
The FHL website or companies that are used to operate this website may place a “cookie” on your computer in order to allow you to use the website and to personalize your experience. FHL also uses cookies and other technologies to help manage online advertising on third-party websites. These technologies allow us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website. They also allow us to collect information about your online activities over time and across third party websites so we can manage advertising effectiveness and provide you with online advertisements relevant to you.

A “cookie” is a small piece of data that can be sent by a Web server to your computer, which then may be stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies are useful in allowing more efficient login for users, tracking transaction histories, preserving information between sessions, and improve the functionality of the website. Some Web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer and Google Chrome may have features that can notify you when you receive a cookie or prevent cookies from being sent. If you disable cookies, however, you may not be able to use certain personalized functions of this website. For more information about online behavioral advertising and your choice to opt-out of receiving targeted online advertisements from members of the Digital Advertising Alliance, please visit their website at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>/. To learn how you can opt-out of Google’s use of cookies, please visit Google’s Ad Settings at <https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated>.

In addition to the use of cookies, we may use certain third-party services, such as Google Analytics, to help us analyze how people use the website. We use this information to evaluate your and other users’ use of the website, compiling reports on website activity, and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage.

**SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS**

The FHL website includes social media features such as social media widgets that allow you to link to a social media website or share website content. These social media features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interactions with these social media features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**EXTERNAL LINKS  
**  
This Privacy Policy only governs the use and disclosure of your Personal Information in conjunction with your use of this website. The FHL website may contain links to other websites, including those of advertising or third-party content providers who offer downloads on FHL. Please be aware that FHL is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites. FHL encourages you to read the privacy statements provided by other websites before you provide personally identifiable information to them  
.  
**CHOICE/OPT-OUT  
**  
FHL may send you emails from time to time related to news updates, online transactions, donations, events, security, or the administration of its website. From time to time, FHL may also wish to send you other messages or updates about FHL and its activities. If you do not wish to receive these communications from FHL, please send an email containing your request to [privacy@thehighline.org](mailto:privacy@thehighline.org) with the word “Unsubscribe” in the subject line.

You will also have regular opportunities to opt-out by following the instructions listed on FHL’s solicitation materials. Even if you opt-out of receiving promotional material from FHL, we will send you transaction emails and respond to questions from you.

**ACCESSING OR CORRECTING YOUR INFORMATION**

We take reasonable steps to keep your Personal Information accurate and complete. If you would like us to consider providing you access to, or making a correction to, your Personal Information maintained in our records, please send your request to us at [privacy@thehighline.org](mailto:privacy@thehighline.org).

**CONSENT OF DATA TRANSFER OF NON-U.S. RESIDENTS  
**  
FHL is located in the United States, its services are provided in the United States, and its data is stored in the United States. Data protection laws in the United States may be different from those of your country of residence. If you voluntarily submit Personal Information to us while located or residing in a country outside the United States, you understand that you are voluntarily agreeing to the use and processing of such information as provided under this Privacy Policy, including transfer of your information to the United States, a jurisdiction which may not offer the same framework for the protection of Personal Information as the jurisdiction in which you are located.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY  
**  
FHL reserves the right to modify or supplement this policy at any time, in its sole discretion, so please check back frequently. The “Last Updated” date will be updated when changes to this Privacy Policy are made. The terms of our current Privacy Policy supersede all previous notices or statements regarding FHL’s privacy practices. The terms of our current Privacy Policy apply to all information stored in our records, regardless of when that information was collected.

**CONTACTING US  
**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the information practices of FHL, please contact [privacy@thehighline.org](mailto:privacy@thehighline.org).

**EU BASED USERS AND THE EU GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (“GDPR”)  
**  
If the processing of your Personal Information is subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), whenever we use or share Personal Information, we ensure that we have identified a legal basis under which such processing may occur. When we use your Personal Information in connection with a request, order, transaction, or to provide you with services that you requested (such as use of the website or to register for events), we do this because it is necessary for the performance of an agreement with you. Further, to the extent the GDPR is implicated, where we use your Personal Information in relation to improvement, development, or marketing of our products or services, for reasons of safety and security, or to satisfy regulatory requirements, other than in connection with our agreement or request, we do this on the basis of our (or a third party’s) legitimate interests or with your consent, as required.

**Access, Modification, Erasure, or Restriction of Personal Information  
**  
If the processing of your Personal Information is subject to the GDPR, you may have the right to access or modify your Personal Information, including the right to:  
• obtain confirmation that we hold Personal Information about you;  
• request access to and receive information about the Personal Information we maintain about you;  
• receive copies of the Personal Information we maintain about you;  
• update and correct inaccuracies in your Personal Information;  
• object to the processing of your Personal Information, request portability; and  
• have the information blocked, anonymized or deleted, as appropriate.

You may also contact us with the request to withdraw consent for processing or storage of your Personal Information. These rights are only available if you reside in, or access the website from, certain jurisdictions and may be limited in some circumstances by local laws and regulations.

**Exercising Your Rights Under the GDPR  
**  
You can exercise these rights under the GDPR by contacting us as [privacy@thehighline.org](mailto:privacy@thehighline.org). Please put the statement “GDPR Privacy Rights” in the subject line of your request, and include your name, country or region, and enough information to allow us to respond to our request in the body of your e-mail.

**Questions or Concerns about this Privacy Policy**

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please first contact FHL at [privacy@thehighline.org](mailto:privacy@thehighline.org) and provide us the opportunity to make it right. For our users located in the European Union or the European Economic Area, if you feel that, after reaching out to us with your question or concerns, you have not received a satisfactory response, you have the option to contact your country’s Data Protection Authority (“DPA”) or similar regulatory body. To find contact information for your country’s DPA or similar body, please refer to the list provided on the website of the European Commission.

### Donor Privacy Policy

**PURPOSE**

Friends of the High Line believes in respecting the privacy of all of its donors. In addition to the terms of our general online privacy policy, this Donor Privacy Policy applies specifically to our donors (both online and offline).

**DONOR INFORMATION: COLLECTION AND USE BY FRIENDS OF THE HIGH LINE**

We collect your name, address, account numbers, and other personal data you provide when you donate to us. We only use that information to process your donation, and to keep you informed about our activities including our programs, special events, and funding needs. If at any time you choose not to receive email communications, you may unsubscribe by following the instructions in our solicitation materials, or contacting our membership office. Note that we will continue to send you transaction emails and respond to questions from you.

We publish a donor recognition list of donors who contribute over a certain threshold. However, we will always take reasonable steps to respect any donor requests to remain anonymous.

If you wish to remain anonymous, or wish to unsubscribe from our contact lists, please contact us at [members@thehighline.org](mailto:members@thehighline.org), or by calling 212-206-9922.

**RESPECTING THE PRIVACY OF YOUR INFORMATION: THIRD PARTIES**

We may occasionally share certain donor names and physical addresses with carefully selected nonprofit organizations, and we may receive a list of their donors in return, to expand our supporter network. While we do not currently share donor email addresses with any unaffiliated third-parties, we reserve the right to do so in the future. If you do not want your information exchanged with other nonprofit organizations, please contact our Membership Department to ask that your name and address be removed from any shared mailing lists at [members@thehighline.org](mailto:members@thehighline.org), or by calling 212-206-9922.

**LEGAL OBLIGATION FOR RELEASE OF INFORMATION**

In certain circumstances, we may be legally obligated to disclosed certain donor information, such as in response to a subpoena, governmental request, or investigation, or as otherwise required by law. We reserve the right to comply with its legal obligations, or to defend itself as part of any legal process.

**CHANGES TO THIS DONOR PRIVACY POLICY  
**  
We reserve the right to modify or supplement this Donor Privacy Policy at any time, so please check back frequently. The “Last Updated” date will be updated when changes to this Privacy Policy are made. The terms of our current Donor Privacy Policy apply to all donor information stored in our records, regardless of when that information was collected.

**CONTACTING US  
**  
If you have any questions about this Donor Privacy Policy or our donor practices, please contact our membership office at [members@thehighline.org](mailto:members@thehighline.org), or by calling 212-206-9922.
